On a weekly basis, The SCOAN receives hundreds of visitors from around the world.
They come to the church for a spiritual retreat and to seek the face of God, for solution
to various challenges they may be having.
They come to where they have seen the Word of God working in the Spirit.
These visitors, who have just arrived from the international airport, after being picked up
and driven to the church, are walking into the entrance of The SCOAN to be received.
As the visitors step off the buses, one visitor begins to run
as the evil spirits within her instantly begin to manifest.
Let's watch what happened next.
Let me kill you - T.B. Joshua, I came to you today!
I am an ancestral spirit.
How many of you are in this body?
We are 65 demons.
Name them.
We are so many – Lucifer.
Number two?
Subian.
Number three?
Maymona.
Number four?
Jabaal.
What have you done to her, you 65 demons?
We sleep with her.
We ate her uterus; we don’t want her to bear a child.
What have you done to her family, her career?
Her family – we killed her husband.
Why did you kill her husband?
We don't want her to be married.
We gave her diabetes and HIV; through an operation, we gave her the HIV virus.
My mission is not this lady, I want to destroy the man of God.
Which man of God?
T.B. (Joshua)
International Visitors Arrive At The SCOAN
He delivers people; even this lady is going to be delivered.
We don’t want that because this lady, when she is delivered, she will be the finger of God.
We don’t want to hear these foolish things – she has already started.
Oo, terribly!
Speak out, demon!
Terribly!
Speak out!
F_ck you.
You must speak!
Which man of God you want to destroy?
Speak out, demon!
Man of the house.
Man of "tuberculosis".
Which man of God?
Name him.
No!
Why don't you want to say his name?
You don’t see the fire?
I made a mistake.
When I arrived, I made a mistake – I was planning to hide until she got back to Tanzania
but she kneeled down to obey your God, that's why I am now chained.
You are chained?
Yes.
Now, I don’t want to go myself, I want to go with the man of God.
Why do you want to destroy the man of God?
The man of God wants to deliver this crowd here.
Which crowd?
You mean the people here?
Yes.
Can't you see?
So, because he wants to deliver this crowd, people that came here, that's why you came here to destroy...
Yes.
Also this lady – why?
The purpose – to have an accident through the flight today.
Speak louder!
To have an accident through the flight today.
There were so many people from South Africa and Tanzania.
I wanted to kill them.
Jesus came and rescued the plane.
The plane took about 30 minutes before--
International Visitors Arrive At The SCOAN
You said what?
The plane lost direction for about 30 minutes in the air.
OK, those of you who arrived in that plane now -
we just want one or two to come out and explain this incident.
Yeah, I noticed this issue.
About 30 minutes before landing, I started thanking God thinking that we were landing.
I praised Jesus; I praised God but it didn't land.
I then started asking myself, "Why is it taking time to land?"
It was me – I am the lucifer.
What was your plan about the plane?
I always need blood!
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
When we were just about to land, something happened -
the flight was shaking uncontrollably.
I asked myself, "Is it turbulence? What is it? Is it because it was raining when we arrived?"
This is a serious issue.
I wanted to cause shame for T.B. Joshua for the second time but I failed.
Which one was the first?
Speak louder!
Do you remember?
Say it!
Did you forget?
South Africa.
It was me; we drink blood!
So, the reason for crashing the plane was to take blood?
Yes.
Speak louder!
Yes, in the kingdom.
Even her blood because she did not obey our instruction.
I told her not to serve your Lord but she refused.
I am powerless but I want to kill.
The international visitors are shocked by the confession of the demons they just heard.
They learnt that where the light of God is, darkness has no hiding place.
That Sunday anointing was in the house.
As Prophet T.B. Joshua moved around mightily, in the power of the Holy Ghost, in the name of Jesus Christ,
the lightning power of God dispelled all shades of darkness in people's lives.
Here, the lady receives her own touch separating her from the evil spirits that once tormented her life.
TESTIMONY TIME
Emmanuel!
(God With Us – Matthew 1:23)
My name is Beatha.
I came from Tanzania.
I thank God for my deliverance which I got last week.
My testimony goes like this:
When I was about 5 to 6 years old, I started having bad dreams,
seeing insects, snakes and eating in the dream; things went bad in my life.
There was a time when my mum told me to go to a shop.
I took just a few minutes.
When my mother blinked her eyes, I had already run out.
The distance was far from our house.
I'm sorry to cut you, madam.
What you are explaining is that right from a young age, you began having these very strange nightmares.
Can you just describe for us again what were you seeing in the dreams, right from a young age?
In the dreams, I used to see snakes and insects,
eating in the dreams and being chased by snakes.
As you became older, what began to happen to you?
How did these spirits begin to affect your life negatively?
It affected my life.
When I was 7, my father had two wives.
He asked me and my little sister to live in my stepmother's house.
During that period, my stepmother used to wash me in the middle of the doorway in a big basin
while I was still wearing my underwear.
She dug a grave in which she put the particles from my body together with my underwear and began to chant.
So, at a very young age your stepmother actually did a ritual
whereby she washed you inside of this occultic basin and actually used all of the residue from
that water on your clothing, items and put it inside a grave and made some incantations.
This is how from a young age these evil spirits began to afflict your life.
As you became older, what were the things that you began to experience?
I started my menstrual period late; when I was between 22 and 24, I had my first menstruation.
Six months after that, I started having abdominal pain
and my stomach became swollen like a six months pregnancy.
My aunt – my father's sister – is a doctor.
She said that she needed to operate on me to see what was inside my womb.
When it was close to the day of the operation, I dreamt of a big snake coming out of my private part
and it entered my aunt and she swallowed it.
In the morning, I told my mother and father about the dream but they didn’t understand.
I went to the theatre that day and my operation took about 12 hours.
The doctor who I saw in the dream swallowing the snake started fighting other doctors
who were in the theatre.
The fight was too much according to what they told me.
There were four doctors but she chased the other three out.
Only my aunt remained and she cut my uterus and ate it.
They saw this from the window.
After 30 minutes, my aunt came to my side in another room and told me three things.
She asked, "Are you OK?"
I said, "I am OK".
She told me, "You are not going to have your own child as I have swallowed all your babies.
Secondly, you cannot be married and thirdly, you are going to be sick".
This is what she told you physically?
This was what she told me physically after the doctors had told me about the incident.
We can understand how these evil spirits really had entered our sister's life and afflicted her,
right from her tender age.
Sister, just tell us, as you were growing up, what actually happened, for example in the area of your marriage.
Tell us what happened when you tried to go into a marriage.
Due to my desire to have children, I decided to get married but I didn't stay in my martial home;
I went home after six months.
Then, I got married to another man who later passed away after three years of marriage.
So, both attempts to get married, the first marriage - you left the man just after 6 months,
the second marriage - the man actually passed on just after a couple of years of marriage.
And you were unable to have children in both marriages?
Yes.
OK, just tell us about your career.
How did these evil spirits really affect you in your career as a medical doctor?
It affected me.
Sometimes in my working place, I used to see dead people coming from everywhere.
It meant I should be there to satisfy the dead, in order to go to the mortuary.
This happened frequently in my life.
My career was nothing.
I had nothing in my hand.
We want to understand clearly.
You mean as a medical doctor when you were in the hospital, as you were on shift,
you would see the people that had died?
You would actually physically see the spirits of those dead people?
Yes.
OK, we can just once again--
Brethren, we are just asking these questions to understand how our sister was really being tormented
by these evil spirits that possessed her right from a very tender age and how it destroyed her marriage,
health, family, career, everything about her, even as a medical doctor.
Madam, we thank God that you came to The SCOAN.
Can you just tell us how did you decide to come here to The SCOAN
and what happened when you decided to come here?
Before then, I adopted a child but the spirit didn't allow me to live peacefully with the child.
I used to beat her.
I thank God because as I started watching Emmanuel TV, I decided to come here.
Three weeks before coming here, I was kidnapped.
All my ATM cards were blocked and they withdrew the money from both my accounts.
By the grace of God, I had already paid for my ticket to come here.
OK, so we want to clearly understand what our sister is saying.
She is saying that several months ago she started watching Emmanuel TV
and made the decision to come to The SCOAN.
Once it was confirmed that she would come, she began to experience a strange attack.
She said that actually her credit cards were all stolen
and people actually began to take money from her bank accounts.
You mean, sister, that every attempt was made to try to stop you from coming to The SCOAN, is that right?
Yes.
This is exactly to confirm what the man of God said that once you make a decision to come to The SCOAN,
we know that anything close to Jesus receives attack.
This was the attack our sister actually experienced before she came here.
Madam, tell us, on the journey here, when you were on the plane, can you describe to us what happened?
In the plane, I started feeling very bad and I started praying and read Psalm 51 three times.
I told the lady sitting beside me, "This plane is not going to land safely. Please, can you pray?"
She said, "I am praying".
I said, "No. I didn’t see your mouth praying".
I was just suffering.
For about 30 to 35 minutes, the plane was not able to land.
The plane went down and up several times.
When the plane finally reached the airport, it landed that way and nearly went off-track.
We thank God because if it was not for your prayers
and the prayers of Prophet T.B. Joshua, we don't know where we would be.
I hope we have listened what our sister is saying.
This was the experience as she actually physically travelled here to The SCOAN.
We saw on the clip earlier how the demon within our sister actually confessed that he had planned
to cause a very serious accident with a plane, that was actually bringing hundreds of pilgrims
here to The SCOAN from different countries.
But glory be to God Almighty that our sister is here in our midst.
She has been completely delivered from that evil spirit.
Now, sister, when you physically came to The SCOAN and arrived at the church -
can you just describe what happened?
Before coming here, I prayed that before entering the church premises, I wanted to kneel down
and obey the God of Prophet T.B. Joshua because of what I had witnessed on Emmanuel TV.
That was what I did but after that, I couldn't remember what was going on.
The last thing you remember is just kneeling down to pray as you arrived in the church
and after that, you can't remember what happened next?
Yes.
Everything we saw on the clip, what we are seeing now, that manifestation, the confession of that demon,
you had no idea what was happening at that moment?
None at all.
Brethren, we can see that truly this was a spiritual deliverance that was taking place
and our sister was afflicted by that demon that had planned to use her to cause so much destruction,
not only in her life but in the lives of the hundreds that actually came to The SCOAN.
But to the glory of God that spirit was defeated and today our sister is here in our midst.
Sister, we know that after this encounter whereby that evil spirit was exposed and was chained,
on Sunday Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed for you.
Tell us - ever since then, what are the changes that you have seen in your life?
I have peace in my heart.
I used medication for diabetes but since I came here, I could eat rice without feeling anything.
I am strong.
I thank God.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Testimony Time
I want to sing a song.
OK, just before the song, madam, you said that before you were having these terrible nightmares,
seeing snakes, different insects, animals--
Ever since you came here, how have you been sleeping?
I sleep well like a baby.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We have heard it from our sister here; physically, her health has been restored.
We heard how the demon confessed that it had caused so many sicknesses in her body.
But she said that since she has arrived here, she has been healthy, eating any type of food,
not taking the medication she once depended on.
And spiritually as well, she is having peace in her heart, and she has been sleeping so well,
to the glory of God Almighty.
Madam, we know in your own case, you just entered the church and your deliverance happened.
What is your own word of advice to our viewers all over the world and those who are present here?
If you are not able to come here, you can touch the Emmanuel TV screen at home.
Just put your faith in Jesus Christ and He will take all your problems away.
I thank the Lord.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!